<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>data-visualization | AICell Lab</title><link>https://aicell.io/tag/data-visualization/</link><atom:link href="https://aicell.io/tag/data-visualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>data-visualization</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://aicell.io/media/icon_hubbd5b6736a681e06d544a07516505556_1406139_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>data-visualization</title><link>https://aicell.io/tag/data-visualization/</link></image><item><title>Introducing Weize Xu: A Visiting PhD Student Joins AICell Lab</title><link>https://aicell.io/post/welcome-weize/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aicell.io/post/welcome-weize/</guid><description>&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re pleased to announce that Weize Xu will be joining us as a visiting PhD student starting in November. He brings with him a background in bioinformatics and software development.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="getting-to-know-weize">Getting to Know Weize&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Weize comes to us from Huazhong Agricultural University in Wuhan, China. He has balanced his interests in Veterinary Medicine and Computer Science to explore bioinformatics tools.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Weize has worked on several projects during his academic journey, including developing software tools for bioinformatics analysis. These tools have been well-received in the academic community and have eased the workflow for researchers.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="synergy-with-aicell-labs-focus-areas">Synergy with AICell Lab’s Focus Areas&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Weize will play a pivotal role in enhancing our existing software tools such as &lt;a href="https://imjoy.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ImJoy&lt;/a>. He will also contribute to the development of visualization tools on top of &lt;a href="https://kaibu.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kaibu&lt;/a>, and web applications via &lt;a href="https://aicell.io/project/bioengine/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BioEngine&lt;/a> for scalable image analysis. All of these efforts will feed into our &lt;a href="https://aicell.io/project/ai4life/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AI4Life project&lt;/a>, which aims to share AI models for the life science community and promote open and reproducible science.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="a-conversation-with-weize">A Conversation with Weize&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="q-could-you-provide-a-brief-background-about-yourself">Q: Could you provide a brief background about yourself?&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I’m a PhD candidate from Huazhong Agricultural University. I have some experience in bioinformatics and have worked on a few open-source software tools.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="q-how-do-you-think-you-will-contribute-to-aicell-lab">Q: How do you think you will contribute to AICell Lab?&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I think my background in Python and web programming could be useful for the lab&amp;rsquo;s ongoing projects.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="q-what-are-you-hoping-to-work-on-at-aicell-lab">Q: What are you hoping to work on at AICell Lab?&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I aim to develop user-friendly tools for biological image processing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="q-is-there-something-people-usually-dont-know-about-you">Q: Is there something people usually don’t know about you?&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I once caught a rather large carp.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="q-how-do-you-think-this-experience-will-benefit-you">Q: How do you think this experience will benefit you?&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I hope to learn from the talented people here and believe the experience will be beneficial for my academic journey.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="q-how-do-you-feel-about-joining-aicell-lab">Q: How do you feel about joining AICell Lab?&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I’m looking forward to it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="q-if-you-could-dine-with-any-scientist-who-would-it-be">Q: If you could dine with any scientist, who would it be?&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Claude Shannon. I admire his work and would love to discuss his views on information.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="whats-next">What&amp;rsquo;s Next&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re looking forward to Weize&amp;rsquo;s contributions and how they will help us improve the software and tools in the lab. We&amp;rsquo;re excited for him to join our team and contribute to our community-focused initiatives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please join us in welcoming Weize Xu to AICell Lab!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more information about Weize, please visit his &lt;a href="https://aicell.io/authors/weize">profile page&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="acknowledgments">Acknowledgments&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This post was edited with assistance from ChatGPT, an AI trained by OpenAI.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>