<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>multi-omics | AICell Lab</title><link>https://aicell.io/tag/multi-omics/</link><atom:link href="https://aicell.io/tag/multi-omics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>multi-omics</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://aicell.io/media/icon_hubbd5b6736a681e06d544a07516505556_1406139_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>multi-omics</title><link>https://aicell.io/tag/multi-omics/</link></image><item><title>A Warm Welcome to Nils Mechtel, AICell Lab's Second PhD Student</title><link>https://aicell.io/post/welcome-nils/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aicell.io/post/welcome-nils/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-warm-welcome-to-nils-mechtel-aicell-labs-second-phd-student">A Warm Welcome to Nils Mechtel, AICell Lab&amp;rsquo;s Second PhD Student&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>We are delighted to announce that Nils Mechtel has joined the AICell Lab as our second PhD student, starting in January 2024. Hailing from the Rhineland in Germany, Nils brings a wealth of knowledge in computational biology and deep learning, further enriching our lab&amp;rsquo;s interdisciplinary research environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img src="./nils-outdoor.jpg" alt="Mechtel in the great outdoors" loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="nilss-journey-from-the-rhineland-to-aicell-lab">Nils&amp;rsquo;s Journey: From the Rhineland to AICell Lab&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Nils&amp;rsquo;s academic path began in the Rhineland, led him to Heidelberg University for his bachelor&amp;rsquo;s and master&amp;rsquo;s in Molecular Biotechnology, and has now brought him to Stockholm for his PhD. His experience in bioinformatics and wet lab work aligns perfectly with the dynamic, interdisciplinary approach of AICell Lab.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="future-endeavors-at-aicell-lab">Future Endeavors at AICell Lab&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="human-cell-simulator-projectprojecthuman-cell-simulator">&lt;a href="https://aicell.io/project/human-cell-simulator/">Human Cell Simulator Project&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Nils will be instrumental in our ambitious project of building a human cell simulator. His focus on generative AI and multi-omics data integration will be vital in modeling cellular behavior through generative and predictive models. This project promises to revolutionize our understanding of biological systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="an-interview-with-nils">An Interview with Nils&lt;/h2>
&lt;h4 id="q-can-you-tell-us-about-your-background-and-journey-to-aicell-lab">Q: Can you tell us about your background and journey to AICell Lab?&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I was born in the Rhineland and studied in Heidelberg. Now, I&amp;rsquo;m excited to start this new chapter of my PhD at AICell Lab in Stockholm.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="q-how-does-your-expertise-align-with-aicell-labs-goals">Q: How does your expertise align with AICell Lab&amp;rsquo;s goals?&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;My background in bioinformatics and wet lab work fits perfectly with AICell Lab&amp;rsquo;s interdisciplinary nature. I&amp;rsquo;m eager to contribute to the lab&amp;rsquo;s cutting-edge research.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="q-what-are-your-research-goals-at-aicell-lab">Q: What are your research goals at AICell Lab?&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I aim to delve into generative AI, particularly in the context of biological data. I&amp;rsquo;m also looking forward to contributing to lab automation advancements.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="q-whats-one-thing-people-dont-know-about-you">Q: What&amp;rsquo;s one thing people don&amp;rsquo;t know about you?&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I once spent a day in the Indian rainforest, an unforgettable experience.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="q-how-do-you-feel-about-joining-aicell-lab">Q: How do you feel about joining AICell Lab?&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Thrilled! I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to start working on such innovative projects.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="a-bright-future-ahead">A Bright Future Ahead&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We are thrilled to have Nils on board and are confident that his contributions will significantly advance our research efforts, particularly in the realms of computational biology and deep learning.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Feel free to connect with Nils and discuss potential collaborations or inquiries. Learn more about &lt;a href="https://aicell.io/authors/nils">Nils Mechtel&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="acknowledgments">Acknowledgments&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This post was co-edited with the assistance of ChatGPT, a conversational agent trained by OpenAI.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>